June 1983
（殴る音）
ハァ… ハァ…
ハァ…
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter One, The Beginning
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
（圭一(けいいち)）ウ… ウ～ン…
ウ～ン…
Good morning.
（圭一）おはよう
（藍子(あいこ)）おはよう
Good morning.
I'm going.
（圭一）いってきま～す
Oh, Keiichi.
（藍子）ああ 圭一
Thank Rena-chan for the pickles.
（藍子）レナちゃんに“お漬物
ありがとう”って伝えてね
Okay.
あいよ！
It's been one month since
I moved to Hinamizawa.
（圭一）
この雛見沢(ひなみざわ)に引っ越して １か月
For the first time,
I learned that air can smell good.
空気にも味があることを
俺は初めて知った
Keiichi-kun!
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君 おっはよう！
Good morning!
（圭一）相変わらず早(はえ)えな
You're early, as usual.
You could sleep in
once in a while.
たまには のんびり
朝寝坊したっていいんだぜ
If I slept in, I'd make you wait.
お寝坊したら
圭一君 待たせちゃうじゃない
そんときは置いてく
And I'd ditch you.
け… 圭一君 冷た～い！
Keiichi-kun, you're cold!
I always wait for you!
いつも 待っててあげてるのに…
サクサク置いてく
キリキリ置いてく
I'd just ditch you
without any hesitation.
Why are you so cold? Why?
どうして冷たいんだろう？
だろう？
I'm kidding. I'd wait for sure.
ウソ　ちゃんと待ってるよ
アア… あ… ありがとう
T-Thanks...
This weird one who easily
blushes is Rena Ryugu.
（圭一）この すぐ真っ赤になって
ポ～ッとする変なヤツは 竜宮(りゅうぐう)レナ
Oh, I have
a message from my mom.
I've known her
less than a month...
まだ知り合って
ひと月も たってないが―
変わってるのは
名前だけじゃないことは―
Oh, I have
a message from my mom.
...but I know her name isn't
the only weird thing about her.
"Thanks for the pickles."
...but I know her name isn't
the only weird thing about her.
よく分かる
N-No problem.
...but I know her name isn't
the only weird thing about her.
N-No problem.
どういたしまして フフッ…
You're welcome.
（魅音(みおん)）オッ！ 来た来た
遅いよ ２人とも
There you are.
You're both late.
Good morning, Mi-chan!
魅(み)ぃちゃん おっはよう！
いつも遅いのは お前のほうだろう
You're the one who's always late.
圭ちゃん お久しぶり
何年ぶりだっけ？
Long time no see, Kei-chan.
How many years was it?
２日しか休んでねえよ
（魅音）アハハハッ…
I was absent for two days.
レナの律儀さとは別に
マイペースなヤツ
Unlike the conscientious Rena,
she goes at her own pace.
Oh, really. You were so cute
the last time I saw you!
Unlike the conscientious Rena,
she goes at her own pace.
Oh, really. You were so cute
the last time I saw you!
Mion Sonozaki.
こいつは園崎(そのざき)魅音　一応 上級生で
クラスのリーダー役だ
What are you talking about?
Mion Sonozaki.
An upperclassman
who's like the class leader.
So how was it being
back in the city?
An upperclassman
who's like the class leader.
（魅音）
どうだった？ 久しぶりの都会はさ
葬式で行っただけだぜ
慌ただしいだけだったよ
I only went for a funeral.
It was just really busy.
So did you get what I asked for?
（魅音）
…でさ 探しといてくれた？
頼んどいたやつ
I told you I was at a funeral!
（圭一）
だから！ 俺は葬式に行ったの！
Hinamizawa is a small village...
ここ雛見沢は小さな村で
学校どころかクラスも１つしかない
...so it only has
one school with one class.
The class is mixed
ages and grades.
そのクラスも
年齢 学年 バラバラで
It's a lonely village with a total
of about fifteen students.
全員 足しても
15人いるかどうかという寒村ぶりだ
先生も１人
There's one teacher.
学年が違うごとに 違うことを
教えなければいけないのだから―
It must be hard to teach different
things to each grade level.
大変だ
時には 俺が先生に代わって
レナや魅音の勉強を見るハメになる
I sometimes end up teaching
Rena and Mion in her place.
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君は お勉強教えるの
うまいね　分かりやすいよ
You're good at teaching.
It's easy to understand.
When I start teaching,
I lose my confidence...
（圭一）
教える端から自信がなくなるよ
...since I realize how little I know.
自分の理解の浅さが分かるからな…
（魅音）人に教えるには―
They say you need to know it
three times better to teach it.
３倍 理解してなければ
ならないっていうしね
…ていうかさ お前
学年１つ上だろう！
Actually, you're a grade higher.
Why are you learning from me?
なんで俺に教わってんだ？
（魅音）細かいことは気にしない
Don't worry about the details.
（圭一）アアッ…
（ﾚﾅ）ねえ 圭一君
Hey, Keiichi-kun, do you have
plans tomorrow? Do you?
あしたはさ
何か予定とかあるかな？ かな？
えっ？
（魅音）圭ちゃんさ…
You still can't find your way
around Hinamizawa alone, right?
まだ この雛見沢
１人じゃ回れないでしょう？
I guess.
そうだな　街へ行くのと
学校へ行く以外は まだ自信ないな
I'm still not sure how to get to
places besides school and town.
Right, right.
そうそう それでね
あしたね 魅ぃちゃんとレナで―
So for tomorrow, Mi-chan and I...
...want to show you around
Hinamizawa while taking a walk.
お散歩しながら
圭一君に雛見沢を―
案内してあげようよってことに
なって
レナ お弁当 作っていくから
どうかな？
I'll make boxed lunches.
Interested?
もちろん行くでしょう？
You'll come, right?
暇ならな
If I'm free.
何よ その態度！
女の子が誘ってんじゃん！
What's with that attitude?
A girl's asking you out!
暇ならな
（魅音）なっ…
If I'm free.
Keiichi-kun, aren't you free?
Aren't you?
圭一君 暇じゃないのかな？ かな？
I'm free.
暇だ
（魅音）なっ！
I'm glad!
良かった
Hey, I see quite a difference
in how you treat us here.
おうおう 魅音さんとレナさんじゃ
随分と温度差がありますじゃん！
ベーッ！
（魅音）ムカッ！
Rena, let's go out
alone tomorrow.
（圭一）レナ
あしたは２人きりで出かけような
If that's what you want.
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君が それでいいなら
Hey, I was the one
who suggested the tour!
（魅音）ちょっと 案内しようって
提案したのは あたし！
This is called Furude Shrine.
（ﾚﾅ）
ここはね 古手(ふるで)神社っていうの
This place probably
has the best view.
多分
見晴らしが いちばんいい所かな
During the next break,
there's going to be a festival here.
（魅音）次の休みは
ここで お祭りがあるからね
（圭一）ふ～ん…
じゃじゃ～ん！
Ta-dah! Rena's deluxe
boxed lunches, special version!
レナの特製弁当
スペシャルバージョンだよ
う～ん… すごい量だ
Gee, that's a lot.
（梨花(りか)）こんにちはです
（圭一）はぁ？
Hello.
（魅音）オッ！ 来た来た
Oh, there you are.
（圭一）沙都子(さとこ)に梨花ちゃん？
Satoko and Rika-chan?
この２人は 俺のクラスメートの
北条(ほうじょう)沙都子と古手(ふるで)梨花
These two are my classmates,
Satoko Hojo and Rika Furude.
They're underclassmen of course.
…とはいっても
もちろん学年は下だけど
What's with all this excitement?
（沙都子）
これは 一体 何の騒ぎですの？
Can't you tell?
（圭一）見りゃ分かるだろう
We're about to enjoy Rena's
homemade boxed lunches.
これから
レナの手作り弁当に舌鼓だ
I can see that.
そんなの
見れば分かるでございますわ！
Why are you spreading
a mat in someone else's yard?
どうして人さまのお庭で
ゴザなんか広げてますのよ？
The shrine is public!
Don't think it's yours!
神社は公共の場所だぞ
勝手に独占するな！
Keiichi's right.
Let's make this everyone's yard.
（梨花）圭一の言うとおりですよ
みんなのお庭にしますです
ク～ッ！ やっぱり
梨花ちゃんは いい子だなぁ
Rika's really a good girl!
座りな そこ！ 一緒に食べよう
Sit over there!
Let's eat together!
（口笛）
（沙都子）しょうがないですわね
I guess I have no choice.
I will join you all.
せっかくですから
私も ご一緒してさし上げましてよ
There's no room for you
to sit and not enough food.
お前に座る場所はないし
食べる分もない
ベーッ！
（沙都子）なんですって？
What did you say?
（沙都子）ンンッ！
（圭一）や～い や～い！
（ﾚﾅ）大丈夫だよ
It's okay. There's enough
for Satoko-chan too.
沙都子ちゃんの分も
ちゃんとあるから
Nope, I'm going
to have Satoko's share.
（圭一）
ない！ 沙都子の分も俺がいただく
I won't let you!
（沙都子）
そんなことは許せませんの！
Here are the chopsticks.
はい お箸です
（沙都子）
いっただっきま～すですわ
I'm going to eat!
俺だって いただきますだ！
Me too! I'm eating too!
It's nice to be young.
いやはや 若いって いいねえ
Please eat a lot.
There's enough for everyone.
いっぱい食べてね
ちゃんと みんなの分あるから
The hamburger steak is mine!
（圭一）ハンバーグ いただき！
I am not letting you have it!
そのハンバーグは渡しませんわ！
（殴る音）
ウワッ！
Elbowing's against the rules...
（圭一）肘は反則だろう…
Oh, we had rules?
（沙都子）
あら ルールなんて ありましたの？
Eating lunch with
everyone is so fun! So fun!
（ﾚﾅ）みんなで お弁当
楽しいな 楽しいな！
（梨花）
レナのお弁当は おいしいのです
Rena's boxed
lunches are delicious.
（魅音）
んじゃ 今日のところは これで解散
Okay, let's call it a day.
レナに圭ちゃん また あしたね
Rena, Kei-chan, till tomorrow.
Thanks for today, Mion.
It was fun.
（圭一）魅音 今日は ありがとうな
楽しかったぜ
（ﾚﾅ）また あしたね
（魅音）うん！
See you tomorrow!
圭一君も 今日は
つきあってくれて ありがとう
Thanks for coming with us today,
Keiichi-kun. Did you have fun?
楽しかった？
ああ 楽しかった
Yeah, I did.
まだ家(うち)に帰るのが惜しいくらいだぜ
So much that I don't
feel like going home yet.
あっ じゃあさ ちょっとだけ
寄り道してもいいかな？ かな？
Then can we stop by
somewhere? Can we?
（圭一）寄り道？ 遠いのか？
Stop by somewhere? Is it far?
（ﾚﾅ）
ちょっと歩くけど すぐ済むから
We'll walk a bit, but it
won't take long. This way!
こっち こっち！
（圭一）ああっ…
（ﾚﾅ）アハハッ！
今日は久しぶりだから
何があるかな？ 何があるかな？
Since it's been a while,
I wonder what's there. I wonder.
It's been a while?
（圭一）“久しぶり”って…
You wanted to come
to this garbage dump?
レナの用は このゴミの山かよー！
ゴ… ゴミじゃないよ
レナにとっては宝の山だもん！
I-It's not garbage!
To me,
it's a mountain of treasure!
わあ 新しい山だ
ワクワク ワクワク！
A new mountain.
Hurray!
Hey, wait!
（圭一）おい 待てよ！
ウワッ！ いたたた…
Ow...
You can just stay there!
いいよ 圭一君は そこにいて
すぐ済むから！
I'll be done soon!
Are all country girls this tough?
（圭一）さすが田舎育ち…
かなわん
（圭一）ハァ…
うん？
（富竹(とみたけ)）あっ…
ンンッ！ ハァ…
（富竹）ああ びっくりした
You surprised me.
T-That's my line!
（圭一）
そ… それは こっちのセリフだよ
（富竹）あっ ごめんごめん
驚かすつもりはなかったんだ
Sorry, I didn't mean to scare you.
君は雛見沢の人かい？
（圭一）は… はぁ…
Are you from Hinamizawa?
Y-Yes...
僕は富竹　フリーのカメラマン
I'm Tomitake,
a freelance photographer.
I occasionally
come to Hinamizawa.
この雛見沢には たまに来るんだ
Isn't it polite to ask permission
before taking a picture?
（圭一）写真ってのは―
被写体に断ってから撮るのが
礼儀なんじゃないんスかね？
あっ ごめんごめん
メーンは野鳥の撮影でね
Sorry, I usually take
pictures of wild birds.
I've never asked them before.
今まで断ったためしがないんだよ
ハハハハッ…
ハハッ… あっ いや…
（ﾚﾅ）圭一君！
Keiichi-kun!
Sorry for making you wait!
I'm almost done!
（ﾚﾅ）待たせて ごめんね
もう終わりにするから
You had company?
（富竹）連れがいたのかい？
彼女は
あんな所で何をしているんだい？
What's she doing there?
Who knows?
さあね？
昔 殺して埋めたバラバラ死体でも
確認してるんじゃないッスか？
Maybe she's checking out
an old corpse she chopped up.
（富竹）イヤな事件だったね
It was a horrible crime.
腕が１本
まだ見つかってないんだろう？
They still haven't found
one of the arms, right?
えっ？ 何の…
What...
（ﾚﾅ）
アハハッ！ 圭一君 お待たせ！
Thanks for waiting, Keiichi-kun!
じゃ
馬に蹴られる前に退散するかな
Well, I should go
before I get kicked out.
驚かせて すまなかったね 圭一君
Sorry for scaring you, Keiichi-kun.
（ﾚﾅ）待ったかな？ かな？
Did you wait? Did you?
Keiichi-kun?
圭一君？
えっ？
あっ …で どうだったんだ？
How did it go?
Did you find anything?
（圭一）
掘り出し物は見つかったか？
うん！ 聞いて聞いて
あのね あったの ケンタくん人形！
Listen, listen!
I found a Kenta doll!
A Kenta doll?
ケンタくん人形って… あれか？
You mean that?
“ケンタくんフライドチキン”の
店の前に必ず置いてある―
That life-sized model that's always
outside Kenta Fried Chicken?
あの等身大人形の？
Yeah, the Kenta doll!
そう ケンタくん！
はぅ… かぁいいよ
お持ち帰りしたい！
It's so cute!
I want to take him home!
フフッ… あれはゴミだろう
That's trash, right?
お持ち帰りしたきゃ
してもいいんだぜ
If you want to take it,
I'm sure you could.
The Kenta doll is trapped
under a pile of junk.
ケンタくん
ゴミの山の下敷きになってるの
簡単には掘り出せないよ
I can't easily dig him out.
I'll help you tomorrow.
あした 俺も手伝ってやるよ
（ﾚﾅ）えっ？
弁当の恩返しってことでさ
In exchange for lunch today.
あ… ありがとう
Thanks!
Keiichi-kun will help...
圭一君が手伝ってくれる…
ケンタくんをお持ち帰りできる！
I'll get to take
the Kenta doll home!
Hey, Rena, did something
happen here in the past?
なあ レナ
ここで昔 何かあったのか？
あっ…
ダムの工事をやってたんだって
I heard they were building a dam.
I don't know too much about it.
詳しくは知らないけど
They were building a dam?
ダムの工事？
例えばさ
その工事中に何かあったとか
Did something happen during
construction, like an accident?
事故とか…
I don't know.
知らない
（圭一）えっ？
レナ 去年まで よそに住んでたの
I was living
somewhere else till last year.
You were a transfer student too?
レナも転校生だったのか
俺は てっきり…
I assumed...
So I don't know much about what
happened before then, sorry.
だからね
それ以前のことは よく知らないの
ごめんね
（圭一）ああ そうか
Oh, okay.
When They Cry
- Bye!
- See you later!
（女の子）さようなら
（男の子）またね
Let's see...
（魅音）
さてと 今日は会則にのっとり―
I would like to act
according to our rules...
部員の諸君に是非を問いたい
...and debate the merits of inviting
Keiichi Maebara to our club!
彼 前原(まえばら)圭一君を
新たな部員として―
我らの部活動に加えたいのだが
いかがだろうか？
No objections!
レナは異議な～し！
Ha ha ha
Can the peasant
keep up with me?
貧民風情が
私の相手を務められるかしら？
Satoko and I agree too.
ボクも沙都子も賛成しますですよ
It's unanimous!
Congrats, Keiichi Maebara!
全会一致！ おめでとう 前原圭一君
君に 我が部への入部を許可する！
I'll allow you to join!
Hey, explain this!
What's this club?
こら！ 順を追って説明しろ
何の部活だ？
Besides, I never said I'd join!
大体が 俺は
まだ“入る”とは言ってないぞ！
え～ 我が部はだな
複雑化する社会に対応するため―
Our club tries to counter
this complicated society...
...and in prosperity or adversity,
our activities are decided by...
活動ごとに提案される
さまざまな条件下―
時には順境 あるいは逆境から
いかにして…
つまり みんなで
ゲームして遊ぶ部活なのです
Basically, we play
games in our club.
I get it.
ようやく分かった
（魅音）先に断っとくけど…
I'll make it clear first.
We don't play games like house.
ままごと遊びみたいな
レベルじゃないからね
You'd better do your best.
本気で かかったほうがいいよ
I-Isn't having fun enough?
Don't threaten me...
た… 楽しくやればいいじゃねえか
そう すごむなよ
（魅音）甘い！
Weak!
会則 第１条 “狙うのは１位のみ”
Article 1: Strive only for first!
I won't allow that
stance in a game!
“遊びだから”なんていう
いいかげんなプレーは許さない！
Article 2: To do that, putting forth
all possible effort is required.
会則 第２条 “そのためには
あらゆる努力をすること”が―
義務づけられておりますのよ
（圭一）分かった 分かった
I get it.
Complex games will put
him at a disadvantage...
じゃ 難しいゲームは
圭ちゃんに不利になるから…
...so let's play a game
everybody understands.
今日は
誰にでも分かるゲームにしよう
How about ordinary old maid?
スタンダードに
トランプのジジ抜きは どう？
（圭一）余裕だぜ！
Piece of cake.
For a punishment game, first
place can order last place around.
（魅音）
罰ゲームは １位がビリに１コ命令
この辺で どうかな？
How's that?
Bring it on.
上等でございますわ
Okay, let's shuffle the cards.
（魅音）じゃ カードを切って…
（ﾚﾅ）１枚 抜くね
I'll take this one.
These cards are pretty worn.
このトランプ 結構 傷物だな
まさか みんなには―
Don't tell me you all know which
card is which from the scratches.
その傷で そこに伏せたカードが
分かってるとか？
（ﾚﾅたち）ヘヘヘヘッ…
（圭一）ちょ… ちょっと待て！
H-Hold on!
That's not fair!
そんなん ありかよ！
Article 2: Putting forth all
possible effort is required.
会則 第２条 “勝つためには
あらゆる努力をすること”ですわ
Some cards are really distinct,
so you'll notice them fast.
いくつかのカードは特徴的だから
圭一君も すぐに覚えられるよ
B-Bring it on! Don't think
that this'll be a handicap!
じょ… 上等だぜ
この程度でハンデになると思うなよ
ハハハッ！
圭ちゃんの手札を右から言うよ
I'll read your cards
from right to left.
Three, four, nine, jack, queen.
（魅音）
３ ４ ９ ジャック クイーン
グワーッ！
By the way, the odd card
is the jack of diamonds.
ちなみに
ジジは ダイヤのジャックなのです
ウワーッ！
どうカードを入れ替えたって
見え見えですわ
It doesn't matter how you
shuffle them, I can still tell.
フフン…
I'm out!
（梨花）上がりですの！
お… 鬼だ　こいつらは鬼だ…
Y-You're evil.
Just evil.
Rena's not evil, right?
レナは鬼じゃないよな？
S-Sorry, Keiichi-kun.
ご… ごめんね 圭一君
こっちが
ハートの３だよね？
This is the three of hearts, right?
上がり！
I'm out.
ウワーッ！
う～ん…
（ﾚﾅ）や… やっぱりさ…
It's unfair to him if we
don't play with a new deck...
きれいなトランプで やらないと
圭一君に不公平だよ
It's fine. He's a man.
いいの いいの
圭ちゃんだって男だし
これくらいの逆境は
はね返せるよね？
I'm sure you can
endure some adversity.
You can do it.
ファイト オーです
（圭一）う～ん…
Come on, Keiichi. Don't hide it.
ほら 圭ちゃん 隠さない隠さない
This scratched one is
the two of diamonds, right?
（魅音）
この傷が確かダイヤの２だったよね
あれ？
Huh?
あっ 魅ぃちゃんが
カード間違えるなんて珍しいね
It's rare for you
to make a mistake, Mi-chan.
T-That's not it. Kei-chan...
ち… 違う
圭ちゃん あんた まさか…
Did you...
ハハハハッ！
引っ掛かったな 園崎魅音！
I got you, Mion Sonozaki!
You somehow forged
the two of diamonds?
ダイヤの２を
偽装したというんですの？
あ… 味なマネを
するでございますわね
You made a witty move.
You got them back, Keiichi.
圭一 一矢を報いましたです
（圭一）ヘヘッ！
You did it! It was
a close game! It was!
やったね 圭一君
大善戦だよ！ だよ！
I knew you could do it.
さすが
あたしが見込んだだけのことはある
I never expected you
to think of something like this.
こんな手を思いつくとは
圭ちゃん さすがだよ
ウフフッ…
Except you're too late.
…とはいっても
ちょっと手遅れだったようですわね
I'm pretty much
set in last place...
まあ ビリは確定だけどさ
最後に
魅音から１本取れたから大満足かな
...but I was able to get
back at Mion, so I'm satisfied.
そんじゃ
ビリの圭ちゃんには罰ゲームだねえ
Then let's do the punishment
game since you're last.
今日は部活の初日だし
ソフトなのから いこうかなぁ？
Since it's your first day in
the club, maybe I'll go easy.
I wouldn't want you to stop
coming to school all of a sudden.
（魅音）いきなり
登校拒否になられても困るしねえ
ウフフフッ…
（圭一）あっ！ な… なに？
What?
ほ～れ…
Hey...
ほ～れ！
（圭一）アアッ…
Hey...
S-Stop!
や… やめろー！
ケンタくん人形？
A Kenta doll?
I see.
なるほど！ それで レナのヤツ
飛んで帰っちゃったのか
That's why Rena took off so fast.
Thinking that thing is cute...
She's pretty weird.
あんなのが かわいいなんて
変わってるよな レナも
Weird hobbies too, but once
she finds something cute...
（魅音）趣味も変わってるけど
レナのヤツ いったん
“かわいいモード”に入っちゃうと
...she becomes
oblivious to everything else.
後先 見えなくなっちゃうからね
（圭一）
あそこさ… ダムの工事現場
About that place...
The dam construction site...
Something happened
there in the past, right?
何かあったんだろう？ 昔
Yeah.
あったよ
突然“ダム作る”って―
Government officials suddenly
came to evict us and build a dam.
役人どもが一方的に
立ち退きを迫ってきて…
Evict you?
（圭一）一方的に？
だから闘ったんだよ 村のみんなで
That's why we fought.
Everyone in the village.
闘わなければ 今ごろ
村はダムの底に沈んでいたんだ
If we hadn't, this village
would've been underwater now.
（圭一）
よく勝てたな　相手は国だろう？
I'm impressed you won.
It was against the government.
The village's leader and powerful
people petitioned together.
（魅音）村長や村の有力者たちがね
方々に陳情した
東京にも行ったし
いろんな政治家に根回しもした
They went to Tokyo and
negotiated with the politicians.
While doing all that,
the plans got withdrawn.
そうしているうちに
計画は撤回されたんだよ
It was our perfect victory.
あたしたちの完全勝利だった
ハハハハッ…
ふ～ん… 暴力沙汰とかには
ならなかったのか？
Were there any violent
crimes because of it?
Like assault or murder...
傷害事件とか…
殺人…
なかった
There weren't.
I-I see.
じゃ また あしたね
See you tomorrow.
圭ちゃん それ
家に帰るまで消しちゃダメだからね
Kei-chan, you'd better not
erase that until you get home.
わ… 分かってるよ 消さねえよ！
I know! I won't erase it!
よいしょ！ よいしょ！
Hey, Rena!
（圭一）よう レナ！
（ﾚﾅ）ハッ…
あっ！
（圭一）精が出ますな
Working hard, huh?
Keiichi-kun!
What are you doing here?
圭一君 どうしたの？ こんな所へ
事故発生の緊急通報を受け
参上しました
I got urgent info about
an accident and have come.
Where is the injured person?
負傷者は どこでありますか？
えっ？ 事故って？
Accident?
I heard that a Kenta doll
is buried alive in the dumpster.
ケンタくん人形が―
ゴミ山に生き埋めになっているとの
通報でしたが…
な… なんだ びっくりした
O-Oh, that.
You surprised me.
So where's the Kenta doll?
…で どこだよ？ ケンタくんは
Oh, sorry! Here, here!
あっ ごめん
ここ ここ！ ほら…
Here, can you see it
through this crack?
この隙間から… 見える？
Gee, he's totally buried alive.
（圭一）
こりゃ ホントに生き埋めだな
We might need an axe
or saw to get it out.
本気でやるなら オノとか
ノコギリが要るかもしれねえな
あっ ちょっと待ってて ねっ？
（圭一）えっ？
Just hold on, okay?
Hey!
（圭一）おい！
（富竹）イヤな事件だったね
It was a horrible crime.
腕が１本
まだ見つかってないんだろう？
They still haven't found
one of the arms, right?
Hinamizawa worker lynch death
（圭一）あった…
There it is!
“雛見沢ダムで悪夢の惨劇”
Nightmare tragedy
at Hinamizawa Dam.
“リンチ”“バラバラ殺人”
Lynched and hacked to pieces.
They beat the victim with hatchets
and pickaxes in cold blood.
“犯人たちは
被害者をナタやツルハシで―”
“めった打ちにして惨殺し
更に オノで遺体を―”
Further, they cut the corpse
into six parts with an axe...
“頭部 両腕 両足 胴体の
６つに分割”
...the head, arms, legs, and torso.
“犯人のうち１人は
いまだ逃走中”
One of the murderers
is still on the loose.
あっ！
（ﾚﾅ）知らない
I don't know.
なかった
There weren't.
There really was one...
やっぱり あったんだ…
In retrospect, those noisy
cicadas at that moment...
（圭一）あのとき うるさいほどに
鳴いていた ひぐらしは―
今にして思えば
これから始まる全てのことを―
...were probably trying to warn
me of all the events to come.
俺に
教えようとしていたのかもしれない
Of all the things that
were about to happen.
これから起こる全てのことを…
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
Can you believe
in things you can see?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
信じられるの？ 目に見えること
Can you believe
in things you can see?
Can you believe in living?
信じられるの？ 息づくこと
信じられるの？ 私のこと
Can you believe in me?
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
When They Cry.
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Two, The Secret
Chapter Two, The Secret.
あなたは信じられますか？
Spirited Away by the Demon
Chapter Two, The Secret
Can you believe it?